What if I was not human and still behaved the way I did?
如果我不是人类 但我的行为举止就像现在这样呢？
Would you still consider me intelligent?
你还会觉得我是智能吗？
&gt;&gt; You know actually you're right, I wouldn't be able to tell the difference.
你说得对 那样的话我无法区分了
&gt;&gt; Then perhaps there are certain qualities of systems,
或许是系统里的某些特质
both artificial and biological that we ascribe the notion of intelligence to
无论是人工事物还是生物 有了这些特质 我们就会觉得那是智能
&gt;&gt; You know in my career,
你知道吗 在我的职业生涯中
teaching artificial intelligence, I find something kind of interesting emerges.
我是教授人工智能的 我发现了些还挺有趣的事
We often tend to use the word intelligence to describe things that we
我们总是喜欢用智能一词来描述
don't know how to explain.
我们不知道如何解释的事物
Once we can explain them, we just say that they're algorithms or formulas.
一旦我们能够解释了 我们就会说那是算法或公式
They're only intelligent if we can't explain them.
只有我们不能解释的事物我们才觉得是智能的
But I think that definition is problematic.
可我觉得这个定义本身就有问题
First it implies that anything we design can never be intelligent
首先 这意味着我们设计的任何事物永远都不可能是智能的
because we would know how it works.
因为我们知道它们的工作原理是什么
It throws AI right out the window.
所以就不算人工智能了
Also, we consider ourselves intelligent because right now
而且 之所以我们觉得自己是智能的
we don't fully understand how our brains work.
是因为我们没有完全掌握大脑的工作原理
One day thou if we do will we not consider ourselves intelligent anymore?
但如果有一天知道了原理 难道我们会认为自己不智能吗？
And for philosophy that's a fine definition to have.
虽然对于哲学来说 这个定义还不错
But for AI to be productive
但要发展人工智能
our notion of intelligence must not be contingent on how we perceive something.
我们对智能的认知就不能从我们对事物的看法中得出了
Rather it should be a property that emerges out of the system itself.
所谓智能 应该是系统本身浮现出的一种属性
&gt;&gt; Good point.
说得好
We often think of intelligence as the ability to accomplish a variety of
我们总是把智能想成是能完成种种
intellectual tasks just like humans do.
智能型任务的能力 就像人类能做到的一样
A subfield of AI called artificial general intelligence
人工智能有一个分支 叫做通用人工智能
deals with this specific goal.
要实现的就是这个目标
But we are far from replicating the complex nature of human thinking.
但要复制人类思维的复杂性 我们还有很长的一段路要走
Equating intelligence with human behavior will pretty much rule out
追求能和人类一样行动的智能
all artificial systems.
只会把所有人工系统排除在外
Besides, even humans are not great at all kinds of tasks.
另外 就算是人类 也不是样样皆精的
&gt;&gt; Yes, intelligence should be defined within the context of a task.
对的 智能应该联系某个任务来定义
For example, if my goal is to solve Sudoku puzzles,
比如 如果我的目的是解决数独难题
and I'm able to do it with a decent rate of success.
而且我能够以相当不错的速度求得解
Then I can say I am intelligent at solving Sudoku puzzles.
那我就可以说在解决数独难题上 我是智能的
It just turns out that humans are intelligent
所以其实人类不过是
at doing a lot of different things.
在做很多事情上是智能的罢了